const itil = [
  {
    question: "What is ITIL?",
    answer:
      "ITIL is a set of detailed practices for IT service management (ITSM) that focuses on aligning IT services with the needs of business.",
  },
  {
    question: "What is an organization?",
    answer:
      "A person or a group of people that has its own functions with responsibilities, authorities and relationships to achieve its objectives.",
  },
  {
    question: "What is a sponsor?",
    answer:
      "A person who authorizes budget for service consumption activities. 1/3 service consumer roles.",
  },
  {
    question: "What is a user?",
    answer:
      "A person who uses services. Users are distinct from customers, as some customers do not use services directly.",
  },

  {
    question: "What is a stakeholder",
    answer:
      "A stakeholder is a person or a group of people who has an interest in an organization, project, IT service etc.",
  },
  {
    question: "What is utility?",

    answer:
      "Utility is the functionality offered by a product or service to meet a particular need.",
  },
  {
    question: "What is capability?",
    answer:
      "Capability is the ability of an organization, person, process, application, configuration item etc. to carry out an activity.",
  },

  {
    question: "What is value?",
    answer:
      "Value is the perceived benefits, usefulness and importance of something.",
  },

  {
    question: "What is service management?",
    answer:
      "Service management is a set of specialized organizational capabilities for providing value to customers in the form of services.",
  },
  {
    question: "What is a service consumer?",
    answer:
      "A service consumer is a person who consumes services. Service consumers can be categorized as other service providers or end users. Generic role used to to simplify the definition and description of the structure of relationships between an organization and its customers.",
  },

  {
    question: "What is an output?",
    answer: "An output is a tangible or intangible deliverable of an activity.",
  },

  {
    question: "What is an outcome?",
    answer:
      "An outcome is a result for a stakeholder enabled by one or more outputs.",
  },
  {
    question: "What is cost?",
    answer:
      "Cost is the amount of money spent on a specific activity or resource.",
  },
  {
    question: "What is risk?",
    answer:
      "Risk is a possible event that could cause harm or loss, or affect the ability to achieve objectives. Can be used to measure probability of positive and negatives outcomes.",
  },
  {
    question: "What is a cusotmer?",
    answer:
      "A customer is a person who defines the requirements for a service and takes responsibility for the outcomes of service consumption. 1/3 service consumer roles.",
  },
  {
    question: "What is a service provision?",
    answer:
      "Service provision is the practice of providing services to customers.",
  },
  {
    question: "Whats is service consumption?",
    answer:
      "Service consumtion are the activities performed by an organization to use a service.",
  },
  {
    question: "What is service relationship management?",
    answer:
      "Service relationship management is the practice of establishing and maintaining a relationship between an organization and its customers.",
  },

  {
    question:
      "What is a description of one or more services designed to address the needs of a target consumer group is called?",

    answer: "A service offering",
  },

  {
    question:
      "what may include goods, access to resources, and service actions?",
    answer: "Service offerings",
  },

  {
    question:
      "What is a co-operation between a service provider and a service consumer?",
    answer: "Service relationship",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What includes service provision, service consumption and service ralationship management?",

    answer: "Service relationship",
  },

  {
    question:
      "What are joint activities performed by a service provider and a service consumer to ensure continual value co-creation based on agreed and available service offerings?",
    answer: "Service relationship management practices",
  },

  {
    question:
      "What are activities performed by an organization to provide services?",
    answer: "Service provision",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What are activities perfomed by an organization to consume services?",

    answer: "Service consumption",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is a set of specialized organizational capabilities for providing value to customers in the form of services?",
    answer: "Service management",
  },

  {
    question: "What are the guiding priciples?",
    answer:
      "The guiding principles are recommendations that can guide an organization in all circumstances, regardless of changes in its goals, strategies, type of work or management structure. They are enduring",
  },
  {
    question: "What does the first guiding principle, Focus on value, mean?",
    answer:
      "Everything the organization does should link back to the value it is trying to achieve. The organization should focus on what the customer values and not on what it can do.",
  },
  {
    question: "Whats considered focusing on the value?",
    answer:
      "Knowing how service consumers use each service. Encouraging a focs on value among all staff. Focusing on value during normal operations and during service improvement. Include a focus on value in all decision making.",
  },

  {
    question:
      "What does the second guiding principle, Start where you are, mean?",
    answer:
      "The organization should start with its current capabilities and focus on improvement. It should not attempt to start from scratch and build something new.",
  },
  {
    question: "How do you start where you are?",
    answer:
      "Look at what exsist as objectivelt as possible for the customer, or desired outcome, as the starting point. When examples of successfull practices are found in the current state determine if and how these can be replicated or exapnded upon to achieve the desired state. Apply your rsik management skills. Recognize that sometimes nothing from the current state can be reused.",
  },

  {
    question:
      "What does the third guiding principle, Progress iteratively with feedback, mean?",
    answer:
      "Do not attempt to do everything at once. Even huge initiatives must be accomplished iteravely with feedback.",
  },
  {
    question: "How do you progress iteratively with feedback?",
    answer:
      "Using feedback before, throught, and after each iteration will ensure that actions are focused and appropriate, even if circumstances should cgange.Once recieved feedback is actively collected and passed along the value chain.",
  },
  {
    question: "Whats a feedback loop?",
    answer:
      "The output is used to inform the next iteration of the same activity or a different activity.",
  },
  {
    question: "Feed back mechnisms include what?",
    answer:
      "end user and customer perception of the value created by the service. The effectiveness and efficiency of value chain activities. The effectiveness and efficiency of service governance and management controls. Interfaces between the organization and its partners and suppliers network. A demand for products and services.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What does the fourth guiding principle, Collaborate and promote visibility, mean?",
    answer:
      "Working together across boundris produces results that have greater buy-in, more relevance to objectives, and better likelihood of long term susccess.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What does the fifth guiding principle, Think and work holistically, mean?",
    answer:
      "No service or element used to provide a service stands alone. The organization should consider the whole rather than focusing on individual parts. It should optimize the whole rather than a component.",
  },
  {
    question: "How do you think and work hollistically?",
    answer: "Consider the whole value chain. Consider the four dimensions.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What does the sixth guiding principle, Keep it simple and practical, mean?",
    answer:
      "The organization should create simple and practical solutions that fit its needs and add value. It should avoid unnecessary complexity. If a process, service, action, or metric provides no value, it should be eliminated.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What does the seventh guiding principle, Optimize and automate, mean?",
    answer:
      "The organization should continually look for ways to improve. It should automate tasks and make the work as efficient as possible.",
  },
  {
    question: "What are the four dimensions of service management?",
    answer:
      "The four dimensions of service management describe four aspects that need to be considered when designing, developing, and operating a service. They are used to ensure that a holistic approach is taken to the design, development, and operation of a service.",
  },
  {
    question: "What does the first dimension, Organizations and people, mean?",
    answer:
      "Organizations dimension typically refers to the entities or structures that are formed to achieve specific goals or objectives. This can include for-profit companies, non-profit organizations, government agencies, and other types of formal institutions. It encompasses how these entities are structured, how they function, their goals, strategies, leadership, and the various processes and systems that support their operations.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What are the 7 guiding priciples recoomendations that guide and organization?",
    answer:
      "Focus on value, Start where you are, Progress iteratively with feedback, Collaborate and promote visibility, Think and work holistically, Keep it simple and practical, Optimize and automate, understand CX / UX",
  },

  //TF
  {
    question:
      "The purpose of an organization is to create and manage services and product",
    answer: "False",
  },
  { question: "Value is not subjective", answer: "False" },
  {
    question:
      "Acting as a service provider an organization produces outputs that help its consumers to achieve certian outcomes",
    answer: "True",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Only costs imposed on the consumer is considered when the consumer assess the value which they expect the service will create",

    answer: "False",
  },

  {
    question:
      "It is the duty of the provider to manage the detailed level of risk on behalf of the consumer",
    answer: "True",
  },

  {
    question:
      "The same offering can be created based on different products, whic allows it to be used in multiple ways to address the needs of different consumer groups",
    answer: "false",
  },

  {
    question:
      "To create value, an organization must cooperate with the consumers in service relationships",
    answer: "True",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Service relationships are established between two or more organizations to co-create value.",

    answer: "False",
  },

  {
    question:
      "Service provision includes user access to resources, fulfilment of the agreed service actions,and Service level management and continual improvement.",

    answer: "False",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Service consumption includes management of the provider’s resources and service actions performed by users.",
    answer: "False",
  },
  {
    question:
      " When receiving services, an organization takes on the role of the service consumer",

    answer: "True",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The term ‘value’ is used regularly in-service management, and it is a key focus of ITIL® 4.",
    answer: "True",
  },
  {
    question:
      "It is important to be clear about the difference between outputs and outcomes.",

    answer: "True",
  },

  //Capability or resource

  {
    question: "Is the following capability or resource? Financial Capital",
    answer: "Resource",
  },

  {
    question: "Is the following capability or resource? Knowledge",
    answer: "Capability",
  },

  {
    question: "Is the following capability or resource? Infarstructure",
    answer: "Resource",
  },
  {
    question: "Is the following capability or resource? Applications",
    answer: "Resource",
  },
  {
    question: "Is the following capability or resource? Management",
    answer: "Capability",
  },
  {
    question: "Is the following capability or resource? People",
    answer: "Resource / Capability",
  },
  {
    question: "Is the following capability or resource? Organization",
    answer: "Capability",
  },
  {
    question: "Is the following capability or resource? Information",
    answer: "Resource",
  },
  {
    question: "Is the following capability or resource? Process",
    answer: "Capability",
  },
  {
    question: "Is the following capability or resource? Experience and Skills",
    answer: "Capability / Resource",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The means of enabling value co-creation, by facilitatingoutcomes that customers want to achieve, without thecustomer having to manage specific costs and risks.",
    answer: "Service",
  },
  {
    question: "A person who uses services.",
    answer: "User",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The functionality offered by a product or service to meet a particular need.",
    answer: "Utility",
  },

  {
    question: "Uncertainty of outcome.",
    answer: "Risk",
  },
  {
    question: "A person who authorizes budget for service consumption.",
    answer: "providers",
  },
  {
    question: "The perceived benefits, usefulness, and importance of something",
    answer: "Value",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Assurance that a product or service will meet agreed requirements.",
    answer: "warranty",
  },
  {
    question: "A result for a stakeholder enabled by one or more outputs.",
    answer: "Outcome",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Takes on costs and risks. Responsible for the means of achieving ",
    answer: "Service provider",
  },
  {
    question: "A tangible or intangible deliverable of an activity",
    answer: "Output",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A person who defines the requirements for a service and takes responsibility for the outcomes of service consumption.",
    answer: "Customer",
  },
  {
    question: "What are the 4 dimensions of service management?",
    answer:
      "Organizations and people, Information and technology, Partners and suppliers, Value streams and processes",
  },
  {
    question: "What are pestels?",
    answer: "factors that affect all dimensions",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the first demension, Organizations and people?",

    answer:
      "Organizations and people dimension typically refers to the entities or structures that are formed to achieve specific goals or objectives. This can include for-profit companies, non-profit organizations, government agencies, and other types of formal institutions. It encompasses how these entities are structured, how they function, their goals, strategies, leadership, and the various processes and systems that support their operations.",
  },
  {
    question:"What is the second dimension, Information and technology?",
    answer:"Information and technology dimension includes the information and knowledge that is used to deliver services, and the information and technologies used to manage the service value system (SVS). This includes information and knowledge used by the organization to create value, and the information and technologies used by the service provider to manage the SVS.",
  }.
  {
    question: "What is clound computing?",
    answer:
      "model for enabling on demand network access to a shared pool of configurable computing resources that can be rapidly provisioned and released with minimal management effort or service provider interaction.",
  }
];

export default itil;
